Gordimer mss., LMC 2355
Lilly Library
- Additions
  - Russell and Volkening Correspondence (Box 22)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 22)
    - 1965 (Box 22)
    - 1966-1971 (Box 22)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 22)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 22)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 22)
    - 1978 (Box 22)
    - 1979 (Box 22)
    - 1980 (Box 22)
    - 1981 (Box 22)
    - 1982 (Box 22)
      (2 folders)
    - 1983 (Box 22)
    - 1984 (Box 23)
    - 1985 (Box 23)
      (3 folders)
    - 1986 (Box 23)
    - 1987 (Box 23)
    - 1988 (Box 23)
    - 1989 (Box 23)
    - 1990 (Box 23)
    - 1991 (Box 23)
    - 1991 (Box 24)
    - 1992 (Box 24)
      (4 folders)
    - 1993 (Box 24)
    - 1994 (Box 24)
    - 1995 (Box 24)
    - 1996 (Box 24)
    - 1997 (Box 24)
    - 1998 (Box 25)
    - 1999 (Box 25)
    - 2000 (Box 25)
    - 2001 (Box 25)
    - 2002 (Box 25)
    - 2003 (Box 25)
    - 2003 (Box 26)
    - 2004 (Box 26)
    - Gordimer - Schwerrin Negotiations, 1976-1978 (Box 26)
  - Writings (Box 26)
    - Crimes of Conscience Reviews (Box 26)
    - The Essential Gesture Reviews (Box 26)
    - House Gun Movie Rights (Box 26)
    - House Gun Reviews (Box 26)
    - July's People Screenplay (Box 26)
    - Living in Hope and History Reviews (Box 26)
    - My Son's Story (Box 26)
    - My Son's Story Reviews (Box 26)
    - New York Times Syndicate (Box 26)
    - None to Accompany Me Publicity and Reviews (Box 26)
    - A Soldier's Embrace Copyright Registration (Box 26)
    - A Sport of Nature Proofs (Box 26)
    - A Sport of Nature Proofs (Box 26)
      (10 folders)
    - A Sport of Nature Reviews (Box 26)
    - Telling Tales (Box 26)
    - A World of Strangers Copyright Registration (Box 26)
  - Short Writings (Box 28)
    - Allesverloren (Box 28)
    - Afterlie (Box 28)
    - Alternate Endings (Box 28)
    - Another Life (Box 28)
    - The Art of Fiction LXXVII (Box 28)
    - At Last - Luangwa (Box 28)
    - Beethoven Was One-Sixteenth Black (Box 28)
    - A Beneficiary (Box 28)
    - Burger's Daughter (Box 28)
    - Bush-Craft (Box 28)
    - The Changed Face of South Africa (Box 28)
    - A Conference with Some Answers (Box 28)
    - Contribution on Wole Soyinka (Box 28)
    - The Diamond Mine (Box 28)
    - Dreaming of the Dead (Box 28)
    - An Emissary (Box 28)
    - For Dear Life (Box 28)
    - A Frivolous Woman (Box 28)
    - From Apartheid to Afrocentrism (Box 28)
    - The Games Room (Box 28)
    - Gemini (Box 28)
    - The Generation Gap (Box 28)
    - Gregor (Box 28)
    - Hemingway's Expatriates: A Way of Lookin at the World (Box 28)
    - His Girls (Box 28)
    - History (Box 28)
    - A Hunting Accident (Box 28)
    - Introduction to 'Almayer's Folly' (Box 28)
    - Introduction: Nadine Godimer: Troy Lecture (Box 28)
    - Introduction to Naguib Maufauz (Box 28)
    - Joseph Roth: Labyrinth of Empire and Exile (Box 28)
    - Letters to a Daughter (Box 28)
    - The Life and Death of a Male Body (Box 28)
    - Living with a Writer (Box 28)
    - Look That's Me, with Lydia (Box 28)
    - Loot (Box 28)
    - L, U, C, I, E (Box 28)
    - A Mad One (Box 28)
    - The Main Course (Box 28)
    - Mission Statement (Box 28)
    - Mother Tongue (Box 28)
    - Nadine Gordimer: A Writing Life (Box 28)
    - The Need for Something Sweet (Box 28)
    - Newspaper Articles (Box 28)
    - No Time Like the Present (Box 28)
    - Our Common Earth: Planet Earth (Box 28)
    - Parking Tax (Box 28)
    - Partnerships: The World Against AIDS (Box 28)
    - Plenty (Box 28)
    - Prison Letters to a Daughter (Box 28)
    - Read All About Us?: The Media and the Image of Africa (Box 28)
    - Reference: The Codes of Culture (Box 28)
    - Safety Procedures (Box 28)
    - Second Coming (Box 28)
    - The Second Sense (Box 28)
    - Separate (Box 28)
    - Siblings (Box 28)
    - A South African Childhood (Box 28)
    - Tape Measure (Box 28)
    - The Termitary (Box 28)
    - Thirst (Box 28)
    - The Third Sense (Box 28)
    - Unidentified Writings (Box 28)
    - Violence and Mr. DeKlerk's Line of Duty (Box 28)
    - Visiting George (Box 28)
    - What's New on the Rialto? (Box 28)
    - Whose 'Agent of Influence'? (Box 28)
    - Witness: The Inward Testimony (Box 28)
    - Witness: Past or Present? (Box 28)
    - You Name It (Box 28)
    - Re: A Present for a Good Girl correspondence and financial documents, 1955-1993 (Box 29)
    - Re: Friday's Footprint correspondence and financial documents, 1959-1976 (Box 29)
    - Re: Not for Publication correspondence and financial documents, 1965-1991 (Box 29)
    - Re: Occasion for Loving correspondence and financial documents, 1962-1969 (Box 29)
    - Re: Six Feet of the Country correspondence and financial documents, 1955-1990 (Box 29)
    - Re: The Late Bourgeois World correspondence and financial documents, 1966 (Box 29)
    - Re: The Lying Days correspondence and financial documents, 1953-1961 (Box 29)
    - Re: The Soft Voice of the Serpent correspondence and financial documents, 1959-1990 (Box 29)
    - Re: World of Strangers correspondence and financial documents, 1957-1984 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
    - Ken French Films Contract (Box 28)
    - Manuscript Publication Notes (Box 28)
    - Photographs (Box 28)
    - Royalty Statements (Box 28)
      (6 folders)
    - Clippings re: Gordimer, family, and friends, 1949-1973 (Box 29)
    - Wedding invitation, 6 March 1949 (Box 29)
- Index to Titles (Box 29)
  A
  Abroad Box 4, f. 27; Box 10, f. 23; Box 12, f. 2
  Achebe, Gift of Africa See: At the Crossroads of Cultures
  Across the Veld Box 4, f. 28
  Africa 1960: The Great Period See: Congo
  Africa Emergent Box 4, f. 29; Box 10, f. 23; Box 12, f. 2
  The African Magician Box 4, f. 30; Box 12, f. 2, 8
  African Literature See: The Black Interpreters: Notes on African Writing
  The African Pot Box 4, f. 31
  African Writing See: The Black Interpreters: Notes on African Writing
  After Apartheid: Black and White in a New South Africa Box 4, f. 32
  Ah, Woe is Me Box 12, f. 2
  Alberto Moravia's Africa Box 4, f. 33
  Allan Boesak: Choosing for Justice Box 4, f. 34 - 36
  Amnesty Box 4, f. 37; Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  Apartheid Box 4, f. 38
  Apartheid, the Agitator Box 4, f. 39
  Apprentices of Freedom See: Relevance and Commitment
  Art and Change Box 4, f. 40
  As I See South Africa Today Box 4, f. 41
  At Last--Luangwa! Box 4, f. 42
  At the Crossroads of Cultures Box 4, f. 43
  At the Rendezvous of Victory Box 13, f. 25, 36, 37; Box 14, f. 3; Box 15, f. 85
  At three o'clock in the morning someone wakes me [first line] Box 4, f. 25
  B
  Babe Box 4, f. 25
  Balancing Rocks Box 4, f. 44
  A Beautiful Day, Com Box 4, f. 45
  Benoni--Son of Sorrow Box 4, f. 46
  A Bit of Young Life Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 12; Box 15, f. 80
  The Black Interpreters: Notes on African Writing Box 4, f. 47 - 51; Box 5, f. 1 - 7
  Blinder See: Love Stories: Blinder and Terminal
  A Bolter and the Invincible Summer See: Leaving School: A Bolter and the Invincible Summer
  The Bride of Christ Box 5, f. 8; Box 10, f. 23
  The Bridegroom Box 7, f. 19, 21; Box 12, f. 2
  A Brilliant Bigot Box 5, f. 9
  Burger's Daughter Box 5, f. 10 - Box 6, f. 10; Box 16, f. 8-9; See also: What Happened to Burger's Daughter or How South African Censorship Works
  Bush-craft Box 6, f. 11
  By the Light of 10,000 Bulbs Box 6, f. 12
  C
  Catalogue of the Ridiculous See: A Morning in a Library
  The Catch Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 18
  Censors, Poets, and Apartheid Box 6, f. 13
  Censorship and Its Aftermath Box 6, f. 14
  Censorship--The Final Solution Box 6, f. 15
  Charmed Lives Box 13, f. 12
  Check Yes or No Box 7, f. 19, 21
  Chief Luthuli Box 6, f. 16, 17
  Children with the House to Themselves Box 6, f. 18
  A Chip of Glass Ruby Box 6, f. 19; Box 12, f. 2, 8; Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  A Christmas in the South Box 6, f. 20
  The Cicatrice Box 13, f. 12
  City Lovers Box 6, f. 27; Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  A City of the Dead, a City of the Living Box 13, f. 27, 37; Box 14, f. 1, 3; Box 15, f. 85
  Clowns in Clover Box 13, f. 12
  The Colour of Want Box 6, f. 22
  A Company of Laughing Faces Box 6, f. 23; Box 12, f. 2, 8
  Comrades Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 15, f. 86
  Congo Box 6, f. 24 - 26
  The Conservationist [novel] Box 6, f. 27 - 34
  The Conservationist [short story] Box 6, f. 35
  A Correspondence Course [script] Box 6, f. 37
  A Correspondence Course [short story] Box 6, f. 36; Box 13, f. 28; Box 14, f. 1, 3
  Country Lovers Box 6, f. 38 - 43; Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  The Credibility Gap Box 6, f. 33, 44; Box 10, f. 23
  Crimes of Conscience Box 13, f. 29, 37; Box 14, f. 1, 3; Box 15, f. 85
  D
  David Goldblatt--So Far Box 7, f. 1
  A Day in My Life Box 7, f. 2
  Death, Love and the Fruit-Basket on Carmen Miranda's Head Box 7, f. 3
  The Delmas Trial Box 7, f. 4
  Diagonal Street Box 7, f. 5 - 8
  Divers with Bloodshot Eyes Box 7, f. 9
  The Dogs Box 7, f. 10
  Don Mattera Box 7, f. 11
  E
  The English Novel in South Africa See: The Novel and the Nation
  English-Language Literature and Politics in South Africa Box 7, f. 12, 13
  The Essential Gesture: Writers and Responsibility Box 7, f. 14
  F
  Face From Atlantis Box 13, f. 12
  A Find Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  The First Circle Box 4, f. 22
  The Fischer Case Box 7, f. 15
  The Flash of Fireflies Enclosed in Gordimer to George Lanning, Jan. 11, 1968
  The Flickering Image: Cinema and the Rights of Man in South Africa Box 7, f. 16
  For Andrina Destiny Was Bitter Box 7, f. 17
  For Dear Life Box 7, f. 18; Box 13, f. 20
  Friday's Footprint [short story] Box 7, f. 19, 21; Box 12, f. 2
  Friday's Footprint [short story collection] Box 7, f. 19 - 22
  From Apartheid to Afrocentrism Box 7, f. 23
  G
  The Gentle Art Box 7, f. 19, 21; Box 12, f. 2
  Germany to Me Box 7, f. 24
  Gold and the Gun Box 7, f. 25 - 34; See also: The Ingot and the Stick, the Ingot and the Gun
  Golden Reclining Nudes of the Desert Box 7, f. 35
  Good Climate, Friendly Inhabitants [film] Box 7, f. 36
  Good Climate, Friendly Inhabitants [short story] Box 12, f. 2, 9
  Gore-Browne of Zambia: Bwana with a Difference Box 7, f. 37
  Great Problems in the Street Box 7, f. 38
  Guarding the Gates of Paradise Box 8, f. 1
  A Guest of Honour Box 8, f. 2 - 7; Box 10, f. 32
  The Guilt of Loving See: Friday's Footprint [short story]
  H
  Happy Event Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 16
  Harry's Presence Box 7, f. 20
  The Hero Box 4, f. 25
  Hillela--A Sport See: A Sport of Nature
  Home Box 8, f. 8; Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 15, f. 86
  Homecoming See: No Place Like
  Horn of Plenty Box 13, f. 12
  The House Gun Box 16, f. 10 - 21; Box 17, f. 1 - 13
  How Not to Know the African Box 8, f. 9
  Huddleston: A Sign Box 8, f. 10
  A Hunting Accident Box 8, f. 11; Box 13, f. 20
  I
  I Am Pascale Box 8, f. 12
  The Idea of Gardening Box 8, f. 13
  An Image of Success Box 7, f. 20, 21; Box 15, f. 81
  The Images and the Man See: Sorting the Images from the Man
  In Celebration of Patrick White Box 8, f. 14
  The Ingot and the Stick, the Ingot and the Gun Box 8, f. 15; See also: Gold and the Gun
  Inkalamu's Place Box 8, f. 16; Box 10, f. 23
  The Interpreters: Some Themes and Directions in Modern African Fiction See: The Black Interpreters
  The Interpreters: Theme as Communication in the African Novel Box 8, f. 17
  Intimate Environs Box 8, f. 18
  An Intruder Box 8, f. 19; Box 10, f. 23; Box 12, f. 2
  An Island of Rock Box 8, f. 20
  It Might Happen This Way... Box 4, f. 25
  J
  A Journey Box 8, f. 21; box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1-7; Box 15, f. 86
  Journey to the Shore of the Dead Box 8, f. 22
  July's People [novel] Box 8, f. 23 - Box 9, f. 7
  July's People [screenplay] Box 9, f. 8 - 20; Box 17, f. 14
  Jump Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  Jump, and Other Stories Box 9, f. 21 - Box 10, f. 7; Box 15, f. 86
  K
  Keeping Fit Box 9, f. 23; Box 15, f. 86
  Kurt Jobst Box 10, f. 8
  L
  The Land Not of Our Brothers Box 10, f. 9
  The Last Kiss Box 7, f. 20, 21; Box 12, f. 2
  The Late Bourgeois World [novel] Box 10, f. 10, 11; Box 15, f. 82
  The Late Bourgeois World [screenplay] Box 10, f. 12
  Leaving School: A Bolter and the Invincible Summer Box 10, f. 13
  Letter from His Father Box 13, f. 30, 37; Box 14, f. 2, 3
  A Letter from Johannesburg Box 10, f. 14; See also: Sorting the Images from the Man
  Letter from South Africa Box 10, f. 15
  A Letter from the 153rd State Box 10, f. 16
  Liberation Knocks Twice See: Tanzania: People, Not Money
  The Life of the Imagination Box 10, f. 17, 24; Box 12, f. 2
  A Lion on the Freeway Box 13, f. 20
  Little Willie Box 7, f. 20; Box 10, f. 18
  Living Conditions: In the Interregnum See: Living in the Interregnum
  Living in Hope and History: Notes From Our Century Box 17, f. 15-20; Box 18, f. 1-13
  Living in the Interregnum Box 10, f. 19 - 22
  Livingstone's Companions [short story] Box 10, f. 24; Box 12, f. 2
  Livingstone's Companions [short story collection] Box 10, f. 23 - 27
  Long Walk from Rhodesia Box 15, f. 81
  Look That's Me, with Lydia Box 10, f. 28
  Lourenco Marques: The Little Escape Box 10, f. 29
  Love Stories: Blinder and Terminal Box 13, f. 31, 37; Box 14, f. 1, 3; Box 15, f. 85
  Lying Days Box 10, f. 30
  M
  A Mad One Box 10, f. 31; Box 13, f. 20
  Madagascar Box 10, f. 32
  The Magic of the Script Box 10, f. 33
  Making Oneself Over: The Swedish Way Box 10, f. 34
  A Man of Africa (enclosed in Gordimer to Tony and Robert, Jan. 5, 1976)
  Man of the Year--Nelson Mandela Box 10, f. 35
  A Meeting in Space Box 10, f. 25, 36
  A Memory of Richard Rive Box 10, f. 37
  The Menace of the Years Box 13, f. 18
  Merci Dieu, It Changes Box 10, f. 38
  Message in a Bottle Box 10, f. 39; Box 12, f. 9
  The Metaphor of Exile Box 10, f. 40
  The Moment Before the Gun Went Off Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 15, f. 86
  More Than a Writer? Box 10, f. 41
  A Morning in a Library Box 10, f. 42
  My Father Leaves Home Box 9, f. 21, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 15, f. 86
  My First Two Women Box 13, f. 13
  My Son's Story Box 11, f. 1 - 15; Box 15, f. 86; Box 18, f. 14 - 16
  The Mysterious Incest Box 11, f. 16
  N
  Naipaul's Freedom Box 11, f. 17
  Native Country Box 11, f. 18; Box 12, f. 9
  The Need for Something Sweet Box 6, f. 8; Box 11, f. 19; Box 13, f. 20
  Neighbors and Friends Box 11, f. 20; Box 12, f. 9
  New Black Poetry in South Africa See: The Black Interpreters
  New Forms of Strategy--No Change of Heart Box 11, f. 21
  New Notes from the Underground Box 11, f. 22
  The Next-to-Last Testament of Nadine Gordimer Box 11, f. 23
  Nice Box 11, f. 24
  The Night the Favourite Came Home Box 7, f. 21; Box 12, f. 2
  No Place Like [short story] Box 10, f. 25; Box 12, f. 1, 2
  No Place Like [short story collection] Box 12, f. 2
  No Place Like: Johannesburg Box 12, f. 3 - 5
  None to Accompany Me Box 18, f. 17 - 20; Box 19, f. 1 - 9
  Not for Publication [short story] Box 12, f. 2, 7, 9; See also: Praise
  Not for Publication, and Other Stories Box 12, f. 8 - 13
  A Note on Women and Literature in South Africa Box 12, f. 14
  Notes for the Definitive Biography: Not for Publication See: Not for Publication [short story]
  Notes of an Expropriator Box 12, f. 15
  The Novel and the Nation Box 12, f. 16, 17
  O
  Occasion for Loving Box 12, f. 18 - 24; Box 15, f. 82
  Old Stock Box 15, f. 85
  Old Times' Sake Box 4, f. 26
  The Old World and the New World Box 4, f. 25
  On and Off the Banned List Box 12, f. 25
  On Sunday mornings in Johannesburg I take a bus somewhere [first line] Box 4, f. 25
  On the Mines See: Witwatersrand: A Time and Tailings
  Once Upon a Time Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  One Whole Year and Even More Box 12, f. 10, 25
  Open House [script] Box 12, f. 28
  Open House [short story] Box 10, f. 25; Box 12, f. 2, 27
  Oral History Box 12, f. 29; Box 13, f. 20; See also: Seek and Destroy
  Orientation--Towards What? Box 12, f. 30
  Otherwise Birds Fly in Box 10, f. 26; Box 12, f. 31
  Our Bovary Box 7, f. 20, 21
  Our Violent Society, Local and Overseas Perspectives Box 12, f. 32
  Out of Season Box 13, f. 13
  Out of the Walls See: The Intruder
  P
  Pack Up, Black Man Box 12, f. 33
  The Path of the Moon's Dark Fortnight Box 7, f. 20
  The Peace of Respectability Box 13, f. 18
  The Pearl of Manet Box 23, f. 34
  The Pet Box 12, f. 10
  The Pickup Box 19, f. 10 - 20; Box 20, f. 1 - 19; Box 21, f. 1 - 2
  A Piece of History Box 15, f. 86
  Plenty Box 12, f. 35
  Policing the University: The Threat in South Africa Box 12, f. 36
  The Political Novel in Africa See: Politics as Fate
  Politics as Fate Box 5, f. 1
  Praise Box 12, f. 37 - 39; Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  A Private Apprenticeship Box 12, f. 40
  The Problems of Apartheid Box 12, f. 41
  Problems of the Novelist in South Africa Today Box 12, f. 42
  Profile: Abram Fischer See: The Fischer Case
  Pula Box 12, f. 43
  Q
  The Quest for Sun Gold Box 4, f. 21
  R
  Rags and Bones Box 13, f. 1, 32, 37; Box 14, f. 1, 3
  Rain-Queen Box 10, f. 26; Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 2
  References: The Codes of Culture Box 13, f. 3
  Relevance and Commitment Box 13, f. 4
  Role of the Creative Writer in Africa See: The Black Interpreters
  S
  Safe Houses Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  A Satisfactory Settlement Box 13, f. 5
  Say Something African See: A Meeting in Space
  Scar See: The Cicatrice
  Seek and Destroy Box 13, f. 6 - 9; See also: Oral History
  Selected Stories Box 21, f. 3 - 4
  Seven Women Artists Box 13, f. 10
  The Shoes Box 4, f. 25
  Siblings Box 13, f. 11, 20
  Sins of the Third Age Box 13, f. 33, 37; Box 14, f. 1, 3; Box 15, f. 85
  Six Feet of the Country [film] Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  Six Feet of the Country [film series] Box 13, f. 14 - 17
  Six Feet of the Country [short story] Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 13
  Six Feet of the Country [short story collection] Box 13, f. 12, 13
  The Skeleton at the Australian Feast See: The Mysterious Incest
  The Sleep and the Waking Box 4, f. 25
  The Smell of Death and Flowers Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 13
  The Soft Voice of the Serpent Box 12, f. 2
  The Soft Voice of the Serpent, and Other Stories Box 13, f. 18
  Soldier's Embrace [short story] Box 13, f. 19, 21
  Soldier's Embrace [short story collection] Box 13, f. 20-22
  Some are Born to Sweet Delight Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 15, f. 86
  Some Monday for Sure Box 12, f. 2, 10; Box 13, f. 23
  Something for the Time Being [film] Box 13, f. 24
  Something for the Time Being [short story] Box 12, f. 2
  Something Out There [film] Box 14, f. 3
  Something Out There [novella] Box 13, f. 33, 34, 38; Box 14, f. 1; Box 15, f. 85
  Something Out There [story collection] Box 13, f. 25 - Box 14, f. 2; Box 15, f. 85
  Something Unexpected Box 14, f. 4
  Son-in-Law Box 12, f. 11; Box 14, f. 5
  Songololo Box 14, f. 6
  Sorting the Images from the Man Box 14, f. 7
  The South Africa I Want Box 14, f. 8
  South Africa: Explaining, Rationalizing, Forgetting Box 15, f. 64
  South Africa: The Way Writers Live Now Box 14, f. 9
  South Africa: Towards a Desk Drawer Literature Box 14, f. 10
  A South African Childhood Box 14, f. 11
  Speak Out: The Necessity for Protest Box 14, f. 12
  Spoils Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7; Box 14, f. 13
  A Sport of Nature Box 14, f. 14 - 26; Box 15, f. 85; Box 21, f. 6
  Spring Box 4, f. 21
  A Stinging Touch of Local Colour Box 14, f. 27
  Story from the Top Shelf Box 14, f. 28
  Stranger in Town Box 14, f. 29
  A Style of Her Own Box 7, f. 20, 21
  Sweet Dreams Selection Box 14, f. 30
  T
  A Tang of Smoke and Indigo Box 14, f. 31
  Tanzania: People, Not Money Box 14, f. 32
  Tenants of the Last Tree House Box 12, f. 11; Box 15, f. 1
  Teraloyna Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  Terminal See: Love Stories: Blinder and Terminal
  The Termitary Box 13, f. 21; Box 15, f. 2
  They were back home again, all three of them [first line] Box 4, f. 25
  A Thing of the Past Box 7, f. 20, 21
  A Third Presence Box 10, f. 26; Box 15, f. 3
  Three in a Bed: Fiction, Morals and Politics Box 15, f. 4
  Through Time and Distance [film script] Box 15, f. 6
  Through Time and Distance [short story] Box 12, f. 11; Box 15, f. 5
  Time and Tailings See: Witwatersrand: A Time and Tailings
  Time Did Box 13, f. 21; Box 15, f. 7
  Tourism Box 13, f. 37; Box 14, f. 1; Box 15, f. 8, 85
  Towards the Heart of Darkness: Congo River Journey See: Congo
  Town and Country Lovers Box 13, f. 21; Box 15, f. 9
  The Train from Rhodesia Box 12, f. 2
  Transkei: A Vision of Two Blood-Red Suns Box 15, f. 10
  The Triumph of Memory Box 15, f. 11 29th October, 1989--A Beautiful Day, Com See: A Beautiful Day, Com
  The Two Souths--One World Box 15, f. 12
  U
  The Ultimate Safari Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  Unchaining Poets Box 15, f. 13
  Unconfessed History Box 15, f. 14
  V
  The Valley Legend Box 4, f. 21
  The Value of a Conference Box 15, f. 15
  A View from the River See: Friday's Footprint [short story]
  A View of the Nile Box 15, f. 16
  Vision of Two Blood-Red Suns See: Transkei: A Vision of Two Blood-Red Suns
  The Visit Box 15, f. 17
  Visit to a Bachelor Box 15, f. 81
  Vital Statistics Box 12, f. 12; Box 15, f. 18
  Vladimir Ledochowski, Man of Two Worlds Box 15, f. 19
  The Voices We May Not Hear See: How Not to Know the African
  W
  A Watcher of the Dead Box 13, f. 18
  Waterford School: The Riches of Human Variety Box 15, f. 20
  West African Diary See: Merci Dieu, It Changes
  What Being a South African Means to Me Box 15, f. 21
  What Happened to Burger's Daughter or How South African Censorship Works Box 15, f. 22 - 27
  What is a Writer's Freedom? Box 15, f. 28
  What is African Writing? See: The Black Interpreters
  What Shall I Write About? See: Writing and Writers in South Africa
  What Were You Dreaming? Box 9, f. 22, 23; Box 10, f. 1 - 7
  When I Lost My Innocence Box 15, f. 29
  Where Do Whites Fit in? Box 15, f. 30
  Which New Era Would That Be? Box 12, f. 2; Box 13, f. 13
  The White Goddess and the Mealie Question Box 13, f. 13
  Who Writes? Who Reads? The Concept of a People's Literature Box 15, f. 31
  Why Haven't You Written? Box 10, f. 26; Box 15, f. 32
  With Open Eyes Box 15, f. 33
  Witwatersrand: A Time and Tailings Box 15, f. 34
  The Worst Thing of All Box 12, f. 12; Box 15, f. 35
  The Writer in South Africa Today Box 15, f. 36
  A Writer's Freedom See: What is a Writer's Freedom?
  The Writer's Imagination and the Imagination of the State Box 15, f. 37
  Writers in South Africa See: South Africa: The Way Writers Live Now
  Writers in South Africa: The New Black Poets See: The Black Interpreters
  The Writer's Responsibility See: The Essential Gesture: Writers and Responsibility
  Writing and Being Box 21, f. 7 - 16
  Writing and Writers in South Africa Box 15, f. 38
  Writing in Africa: Nadine Gordimer Interviewed... Box 15, f. 39
  Y
  You Name It [short story] Box 13, f. 21; Box 15, f. 40
  You Name It [television script] Box 15, f. 41